# ANCA SIMON

#### FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ANCARSIMON@GMAIL.COM

https://asimonbio.web.app

**#** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anca-simon/



https://github.com/ancasimon

### **ABOUT ME**

One of the most vivid memories in my BA experience is the demo where we saw the first iteration of a project I had owned from discovery and market research through mockups, requirements, and now development. Seeing an actual program where before there had been just words on paper (well, on screen) was amazing! Today, I am a developer because of that moment. I love solving technical and business problems and helping users leverage technology to enhance results.

#### **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School: Full-Stack Developer Middle Tennessee State University: MA English Lipscomb University: BA English

#### PROJECTS @ NSS

#### **GEARUP**

GearUp eliminates the stress of packing for outdoor adventures! A single-page React application with CRUD functionality, using Firebase, it allows you to manage your camping gear and trips. Users can create records for their gear, edit, and delete them as well as filter the gear list. They can create and edit trips and quickly put together packing lists for each trip.

**Technologies:** Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, Firebase, FreeLogoDesign, GitHub, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSX, Lucidchart, moment.js, moqups, React, React Router, reactstrap, REST API, Sass, sweetalert2, Webpack

# **FOODIES UNITE**

For the gourmet traveler, Foodies Unite provides meal recommendations for locations around the US and the world. It is a single-page web app with CRUD functionality, using Firebase. I used Bootstrap for the layout, FontAwesome icons for more visually appealing button icons, and JavaScript and jQuery for the program. Users can create and edit boards as well as add multiple cards to each board with details about the dining recommendation.

**Technologies:** Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, ESLint, Firebase, GitHub, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, JSONLint, Lucidchart, moment.js, moqups, REST API, Sass, Webpack

# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Nashville Software School | 2020-2021

Non-profit organization providing intensive accelerated software development programs, teaching full-stack software development fundamentals, teamwork, and problem-solving **Technologies**: HTTP-based, RESTful, and RPC-based APIs; ASP.NET; Axios; Bootstrap; C#; CSS; ES6 Modules; Firebase; GitHub; HTML5; JavaScript; jQuery; JSON; JSX; .NET Core;

Postman; React; React Router; reactstrap; Saas, T-SQL

- Learned object-oriented programming fundamentals and development best practices, including single responsibility principle, DRY code, and modularization.
- Built single-page applications using React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and JSON.
- Used Firebase for data management, Google authentication, and deployment, employed Axios method with the Firebase Database REST API, and wrote Promises to call data across multiple data collections. Bundled projects with Webpack, using ESLint for linting.
- Leveraged Bootstrap components for layout and data display. Used FontAwesome for more visually appealing icons. Took advantage of Google Photos to dynamically upload photos in apps.
- Used GitHub for project planning and version control, mapped out relationships between different data collections in entity relationship diagrams (ERDs) via Lucidchart, and built wireframes for new projects using mogups.
- Successfully collaborated in teams virtually using tools such as Zoom, Google Meet, and Slack.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

**Contracted with TEKsystems for the TN Department of Human Services | 2016** Information technology and services recruiting organization

- Worked closely with business users to document workflows and business and technical requirements for transitioning current COBOL software program to Oracle Forms
- Provided visibility into project progress and commitments by managing project metrics leading the implementation of Agile methodology, and acting as the Scrum Master for the development team

# BUSINESS ANALYST & PRODUCT MANAGER UL Workplace Health & Safety | 2011-2016

Business unit of Underwriters Laboratories, providing software applications and elearning training to help improve the safety of workers across diverse industries

- Drove product strategy by working closely with customers, support, sales, marketing, solutions consultants, and the management team to define the product roadmap
- Managed the end-to-end Product Management process that spans market needs identification to product development to product launch and support
- Ensured product roadmap goals were successfully implemented by collaborating successfully with the development, QA, documentation, and engineering teams
- Planned release schedule, deliverables, goals, and milestones
- Defined technical and business requirements and maintained project documentation
- Increased new sales and customer expansions by providing support to the Sales team, helping with RFPs, conducting demos, and creating roadmap collateral

#### **TECHNICAL WRITER**

Epic Systems Corporation | 2005-2010

Healthcare software provider, offering a centralized site for a patient's information

- Enhanced user adoption of new features by using proprietary tools to provide a wide variety of user materials, including moment-of-need quick start guides, release notes, user guides, online help, design specifications, and test scripts
- Led a new strategy to improve user access to clinical and billing data in order to provide more actionable reporting and contributed to a major revamp of the online help system
- Helped customers become successful users of the software applications and newly released features by leading customer training sessions on using documentation deliverables and by providing onsite go-live assistance